Hey. Hi, everyone.
Hey.
Hi.
Pheebs, what's wrong?
I'm just so exhausted
from dragging around
this huge engagement ring!
Oh, my God!
Congratulations.
So did he get
on one knee?
Did he have a speech prepared?
Oh, did he cry?
Yeah, big surprise--
I like proposals.
It was really sweet,
and like the most
romantic thing ever.
Well, hey, well,
here's to Phoebe--
who's found the greatest
guy in the world.
To Phoebe and...
I want to say... Mike?
To Phoebe and Mike!
Thank you.
Oh, and I have
something for you.
Yeah, it's my
little black book.
It's got the numbers
of all the guys I've dated.
Oh, Pheeb...
That's nice, but
you know what,
I think I'm okay.
Why don't you give it
to one of your other
single girlfriends.
I would, but you're
the last one.
Give me the book!
Pablo Diaz...
Grady Smith...
Guy in van...?
Ah, my first love.
Ah.
What is the red "X" next
to Bob Greenmore's name mean?
Dead.
Oh, it's okay.
No, he was old. Yeah.
And he lived a full life.
He was in the first wave
at Omaha Beach.
I'm sorry, I should have given
you guys my black book
when I got married.
Although it wasn't
so much a book
as a napkin.
With Janice's phone number
on it.
RACHEL:
Phoebe,
isn't Jethro Tull a band?
Oh, yes they are.
♪ So no one told you
life was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's D.O.A. ♪
♪ It's like you're always
stuck in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been
your day, your week ♪
♪ Your month,
or even your year ♪
♪ But I'll be there for you ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me, too. ♪
Hey, honey.
Hey, sweetie.
Is Monica not here?
No.
Then I'll tell you.
My agency was bidding
for a big account
and they got it.
It's my first
national commercial.
Cool.
Yeah, and I don't
want to brag,
but a lot of the ideas
were mine.
Hell, you weren't there.
All the ideas were mine.
That's great.
Hey, can you cast me in it?
Oh, I don't know.
I really don't think
you're right for the part.
What do you mean?
I can do anything.
I'm a chameleon. Huh?
( with gravelly voice ):
I'm old.
( yawning ):
I'm tired.
I am hot.
I'm cold.
Huh, come on, what can't I do?
First of all, bravo.
But I really don't think
you're right for this.
The part calls for
a stuffy college professor.
I can do that.
( with haughty tone ):
Hello. I'm your professor.
When I'm not busy thinking
of important things or...
professing...
I like to use...
Oh, what's the product?
Software that facilitates
inter-business
networking E solutions.
I'm cold.
Hey.
Hey!
Guess who's a finalist
for a huge research grant?
I'll give you a hint.
He's looking right at you.
Huh. Well, unless
it's the creepy guy
with his hand up his kilt,
I'm going to say
congratulations.
I'm so excited.
Apparently, I beat out
hundreds of other applicants.
Including five guys
I went to graduate
school with.
Not that I'm keeping
score or anything.
Five.
Wow, that's great.
Yeah.
So, tell me about the grant.
Well, okay,
it's for $25,000,
and if I get it,
I'll finally be able
to complete my field research.
And there will be
an article about me
in the Paleontology Review.
Yeah, it'll be the first time
my name is in there
without people raising
serious questions
about my work.
Wait. Are you talking
about the Dewer Grant?
Yeah, why?
Benjamin Hobart is administering
that grant.
Your ex-boyfriend?
Yeah.
So your ex-boyfriend
is going to determine
if your new boyfriend
gets this grant?
Wow, your new
boyfriend is screwed.
No, no.
We ended on great terms.
I mean, if anything, I think
this could help you.
You know what?
Why don't we all
go out to dinner together
and I can introduce you.
Well, if you think
it would help.
Absolutely.
I'll call him.
Okay, now, is there
anything I can do
to butter him up?
Anything he really likes?
Hmm... he does have a pretty
serious latex fetish.
We'll see how dinner goes.
( knocking )
Hey.
Hey. You want to go
see a movie?
Well, I told you
I had to spend all day
clearing out stuff
so Mike could move in.
Oh, right.
Oh, well.
Now that I'm here,
I might as well help you
with your cleaning
and organizing.
I just happen to have
my label maker.
Oh, it's so hard
to get rid of stuff.
Did you and Chandler have
to make compromises
when you first
moved in together?
Chandler did.
What does he want
you to give up?
A bunch of stuff.
And the worst one--
he wants me to get rid
of Gladys.
Who's Gladys?
( gasps )
Wow.
What a tragic loss.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, I really hate
to give her up.
Oh, I know!
Oh, you should take her!
I... I... I don't know.
What, you don't like her?
Well, of course I do.
What's not to like?
I'd take her in a minute.
But, you know, I think that
you're giving up
too easy, honey.
I think that you need
to fight for her.
Really, do you think?
Absolutely.
Yes, you say to him,
"I'm sorry, Mike,
"I can't live without her.
She means too much to me."
Okay, I'll fight for her.
Okay.
Oh, wait, oh, I just realized,
if I do that,
that means you don't get her.
Damn it, I did not
think this through.
Hey, guys.
Hi.
Oh, any word on casting yet?
Joe, I told you, you're
just not right for the part.
What do you mean?
Rach, don't I seem like
a professor
you'd buy some kind
of E crap from?
I'm sorry, this sounds
like something
I'm never going to be
interested in.
Look, come on, please.
It's not like I'm asking you
for some crazy favor.
This is what I do for a living.
I am a professional actor.
Oh, man, I'm two hours
late for work.
Look, here's a copy
of my reel.
It's got all the commercials
that I've been in.
Joe...
Just watch it.
And if you don't like it,
you don't pass it on
to your bosses.
Fine.
Thank you.
Work, Joe.
Damn it!
What am I going to do now?
Just pass
the tape along.
He's not right
for the part.
So if I suggest to my bosses,
they're going to think
I'm an idiot.
And that's something
they should learn on their own.
Well, just
tell Joey
that you watched the tape
and you liked it,
but your bosses didn't.
Then, that way,
you're the good guy
and they're the bad guy.
That's good.
I liked it, they didn't.
Joey, for God's sake,
go to work!
I can't believe I'm about
to meet Benjamin Hobart.
I've always thought of him
as one of the people
I'd invite to my
fantasy dinner party.
You think there's any chance
he'll bring Christy
Brinkley or C3PO?
Sorry, looks like
it's just him.
Charlie.
My God, you look
absolutely stunning.
Well, I am having
a good hair day.
It's so good to see you.
You, too.
( clearing throat )
I'm okay.
Um, I'm sorry.
Ross Geller,
Benjamin Hobart.
It's an honor
to meet you.
I mean, I can't tell you
how long I've been
an admirer of your work.
I mean, that Nobel Prize...
Whoo!
I mean, I have
to tell you
that you're one of the reasons
I got into the field.
Oh, well, likewise.
Uh, actually,
not likewise.
I'd never heard of you
until this morning,
but it's nice to be nice.
Oh, shall we?
Yeah.
Thank you.
I can't believe that you chose
this restaurant.
Do you remember the night?
Oh, my God.
I completely forgot.
I can't believe they let us back
in this place.
( all chuckling )
( shrill laughter )
You weren't there.
No, but...
you know, it's just
a funny image, you know,
the two of you
in this restaurant
with... with the... hmm.
Ross, why don't you tell
Benji about your proposal
while I go
to the ladies' room.
Okay?
So, tell me about it.
Okay, well,
I would like to do a dig
in the Painted Desert.
Mm-hmm.
See, there are still
several areas
that haven't been
fully excavated.
Break up with Charlie.
What?
Did... did you just say
"break up with Charlie"?
Well, yes and no.
Yes, I did say it, and no,
I didn't not say it.
Um, kind of inappropriate,
don't you think?
Listen... I'm sorry.
I just haven't
seen her for so long.
All these feelings
are rushing back.
I'm starting to realize
how much I missed her
and I'm going to need you
to break up with her.
Are you serious?
If you say yes,
then I'm serious.
If you say no,
then I'm joking.
No.
Joking it is.
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
Hey. How'd it go with Mike?
Is he going to let
you keep the painting?
No. He really hates it.
But he's going to let me
keep my box of human hair.
So, you got
to pick your battles.
But the good news is,
Gladys is yours.
Wow, what's the bad news?
Who's Gladys?
Oh, she's that
work of art I made--
you know, with the woman
coming out of the frame.
Oh, and Monica
gets to keep her?
In her house?
I am so jealous.
Oh, I didn't know
you wanted her, too.
Well, I mean, sure, of course.
But... you already gave
that to Monica, so...
No, no, I would give
her up for you.
No, I couldn't let you do that.
But I want to.
But I don't want you to.
But I insist.
But I insist harder.
Okay, girls, girls, stop.
Okay, we'll flip a coin.
Heads she's Rachel's,
tails she's Monica's.
Tails. Monica, she's yours.
That landed in your food.
No, no, that's okay.
You won fair and square.
I'm so sad.
Hey, Joe.
What's up?
Bad news.
I watched the tape
and passed it along
to my bosses,
and they weren't
interested.
Oh.
Sorry, man.
Well...
But, uh,
you watched the tape?
Yeah. I-I-I liked it.
But, uh,
my bosses didn't go for it.
Stupid sons of bitches!
You didn't watch the tape.
What? Of course I did.
Look, it's one thing
not to cast me,
but to lie to me?
I'm not lying to you--
I watched it.
There, you lied again.
I watched it!
Keep going, Pinocchio!
I did!
No, you didn't!
I'm telling you,
I watched the tape!
Did you watch
the tape?
No.
So, the selection committee
has chosen the three of you
as our finalists today.
The ultimate decision
will be based
upon the answers you give
to the questions I ask here.
We're going to start
with Dr. Li.
Dr. Li, you claim the field
is too reliant
on the Linnaen taxonomic system.
How do you propose
to correct this problem?
Well, I believe
that the answers lie
in the osteological evidence.
I plan to begin there.
Interesting.
( quietly ):
I guess.
Dr. Biely, your proposal
includes some field work.
Where might that take place?
Primarily
in the Pierre-Shale
region of South Dakota.
Certainly.
Very well.
And, Dr. Geller,
when is my birthday?
What? I... I...
Care to venture a guess?
May 12?
That's not even kind ofclose.
Dr. Li,
how many graduate students
will you be needing?
Half a dozen.
I see. And Dr. Biely?
Three for excavation
and two for analysis.
Certainly.
Dr. Geller,
which 1965 Shirelles hit
was later covered by
a popular British Invasion band?
Wha...? I need six
graduate students.
No, I'm sorry, we were looking
for "Baby, It's You."
"Baby, It's You."
Wha... Wait, wait,
wait just a minute.
None of my questions
have anything to do
with paleontology.
You're right. I apologize.
Scratch the last question.
Spell "Boscodictiasaur."
Um... I've never heard
of a Bosco... dictiasaur.
Yeah, I just made it up.
Spell it.
Okay. B-O...
No, it starts with a silent "M."
Oh, come on!
I can't believe Joey.
I hate being called a liar.
But you are a liar.
What did I just say?
You still here?
Yes,
and I have to say,
I am not just hurt,
I am insulted.
When I tell somebody
I did something...
Okay, hold on,
let me just stop you
right there, okay?
First you lied, right?
Then you lied about lying, okay?
Then you lied about lying
about lying, okay?
So before you lie
about lying about lying
about lying about...
lying about...
Stop lying!
Why are you so sure
I didn't watch this tape?
You know what?
You want to know why?
Well, this is going well.
Here's how I know
you didn't watch the tape, okay?
If you had seen
what was on this tape,
believe me,
you would have some comments.
All right, now,
remember, I got paid
a lot of money for this,
and it only aired in Japan.
Icheban.
Icheban. Lipstick for men.
Seiko.
And that's how I know
you didn't watch the tape!
( door slams )
He really is a chameleon.
Well, Gladys,
say hello to your new home.
Oh, my.
Wow. Oh.
She's so nice and big.
Oh, Monica, where are
you going to display
Gladys, oh, so proudly?
Haven't really settled
on a spot yet.
Oh, hey, how about
right above the TV?
That way, it will be
the first thing that you see
when you walk in the door.
Yeah! Yeah!
And you can get rid
of that French poster.
I like that poster.
Really?
It doesn't have anything
coming out of it.
Or maybe
there's someplace for her
in your bedroom.
Oh! There's nothing
above your bed!
Are you still here?!
Oh, hi.
Hello. Uh,
have you come to ask me
some more paleontology-related
questions?
Um, your grandmother's nickname,
perhaps?
Ann-Margaret's pant size?
I've come here to apologize.
I think I may have let
my feelings for Charlie
interfere with
the interview process.
No. Stop.
Anyway, I decided to
offer you the grant.
Really?
Well, there is just
one small stipulation.
I have to break up with Charlie?
Hey, you got one right.
You're crazy.
Crazy or romantic?
Crazy.
Or...?
Get out!
Oh, my God!
( gasps )
What-what?
Joey,
what is this thing doing here?
I got it from Monica.
She sold it to me for
a very reasonable price.
Joey, we're not keeping this.
But it's an original Buffay.
All right, fine,
you can keep it.
As long as you don't mind
that she's haunted.
Wha-What? Whoa, what? What?
Well, legend has it, Joey,
that she comes alive
when you're asleep.
She climbs
out of the frame
and then drags her half a body
across the floor
just looking for legs to steal.
And then
with her one good hand,
she slowly reaches up
and turns your doorknob...
Get that legless witch
out of here!
Hey, I sold that to Joey.
Yeah?
Well, I told him
it's haunted.
Two can play at this game.
No, too late.
You can't give it back.
Yes, I can.
No, you can't--
she's yours!
She's yours!
Hey.
She's mine!
You guys, you guys, you don't
have to fight over her anymore.
Whoever doesn't get Gladys
gets Glynnis.
( gasps )
I want Gladys!
She's mine!
Look, I'm sorry
I didn't give them your tape,
and I promise next time
to submit you
whether I think you're right
for the part or not.
That's not the point, Chandler.
The point is that you lied.
I know.
You're right.
What's it going to take
for you to forgive me?
Oh, my God.
Excellent.
Now, what do you say?
Lying is wrong.
And?
I'm a pretty little girl.
I knew it.
Your ex-boyfriend is insane.
Did you get the grant?
No, I didn't,
and you want to know why?
Because your ex-boyfriend
is still in love with you.
What?
Yeah.
He wouldn't
give me the grant
because I wouldn't
give you up.
Benji isn't in love with me.
I mean, he broke up with me.
And besides,
he's a very ethical man.
Really?
Is it ethical to
ask someone in
a grant review,
who was the voice
of Underdog?
I'm sure he was
just joking, Ross.
If you don't
believe me,
let's go talk
to him, okay?
I'm telling you,
he didn't ask me
onepaleontological
question.
Seriously?
No, oh, I'm sorry,
no, he did ask me one.
Uh, how do you spell
"Boscodictiasaur"?
Well, if it's like
the Lake Bosco in Congo,
then M-B-O...
Damn it!
Dr. Geller?
Charlie. What are you...
what are you doing here?
I want you to tell
her everything--
about the deal you
tried to make with me,
about the-the crazy
questions you...
Wally Cox.
That's the voice of Underdog.
Like I tried to tell you
in the interview, Ross,
this grant is not based
on your knowledge
of pretty useless trivia.
No, no, no,
don't do that.
I want you to look her in
the eyes and tell her the truth.
Benji?
All right, it's true.
I behaved horribly, but it's
only because I still love you,
and I would do anything
to have you back in my life.
Too little too
late, Benji!
I can't believe this.
I never should have
broken up with you.
I think about you all the time.
I mean,
do you ever still
think about me?
No.
Yes.
What?
I don't know
what to say, Benji.
This is all so... romantic.
Or...?
Listen, I know I may be
way out of bounds here,
but is there any chance
you would take me back?
Maybe.
Sweetie, this
conversation's
starting to make me
a little uncomfortable.
Oh, God.
I am so sorry.
I mean...
there's so much history
between us, you know?
I'm sorry, too.
I-I love you.
I love you, too.
Okay, that's it--
we are seeing other people!
( fabric ripping slowly )
( ripping continues )
Gladys?
( screaming )
Ha-ha!
Third time this week.
Man, this does not get old.
( panting ):
You're mean!
Aw, don't be such a baby.
Please.
( screams )
( shouts )
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org